thebaffler.com 2019-09-01

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy was last updated May 24, 2018. If you have any questions about how The Baffler Foundation stores, collects, or accesses personal information, please contact our data protection officer at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2454564d5245475d64504c41464542424841560a474b49).

By visiting _The Baffler’_ s online magazine (thebaffler.com), store (shop.thebaffer.com), or online subscriber service portal (ezsubscription.com/bfl/mysubscription) you are accepting and agreeing to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. The following paragraphs describe the type of information _The Baffler_ collects, the reasons why such information is collected, how such information is used and who has access to it. There is no advertising contained within any website maintained by The Baffler Foundation other than the marketing of products and subscriptions sold directly by The Baffler Foundation.

### Collection of Information

The Baffler Foundation, as well as third-party vendors used by The Baffler Foundation, collects personal information from users through voluntary submissions and browsing data stored within cookies. Additionally, The Baffler Foundation, as well as third-party vendors used by The Baffler Foundation, collect anonymous information through traffic data and cookie technology. The Baffler Foundation is not responsible for the information practices of third parties, although we take care to engage third-party fulfillment processors, CDNs, email providers, and other support services that respect your privacy, preferences and data security needs.

Wherever possible and practical, The Baffler Foundation gives users options about submitting information. In all cases, The Baffler Foundation strives to promptly export or delete personal data at the request of any user.

All transmissions through websites maintained by The Baffler Foundation are served through a secure connection (SSL). Both personal and anonymized information is stored in secure, encrypted databases which are regularly reviewed by the Data Protection Officer to ensure security.

### Subscriptions

The Baffler Foundation offers magazine subscriptions in both print and digital formats for purchase online, through a fulfillment house, Fulco Inc. The purchase of any magazine subscription requires the submission of personal information like your full name, home address, or phone number. This information is stored by both Fulco and The Baffler Foundation in subscriber databases. Subscriber notifications (new issue alerts, changes to an account profile such as an updated address, or renewal notices) may be sent through email from either Fulco or The Baffler Foundation’s email vendor, Mailchimp. You may unsubscribe from these notifications at any time.

The Baffler Foundation will promptly export or erase any subscriber profile upon request.

### Electronic Newsletters

The Baffler Foundation offers a free weekly email newsletter to which you may voluntarily subscribe and unsubscribe at any time. The use of websites maintained by The Baffler Foundation is not contingent on newsletter subscription. The newsletter is delivered by our email vendor, Mailchimp. When you sign up for our newsletter, you must provide your email address, and you may optionally provide your first and last name. At the time that you sign up, Mailchimp will collect additional data about your sign-up request, such as the type of browser you used and the location of your internet service provider. If you are an existing subscriber to _The Baffler_ magazine, we may associate your subscriber profile with data from your newsletter preferences.

The purpose of collecting emails for our newsletter is primarily to update readers on the content published in either the _Baffler_ magazine or website. We occasionally send promotional content, like special offers to subscribe to the magazine or purchase items from our shop. We do not rent our newsletter for outside advertisement or share the emails from our newsletter list at any time. Through Mailchimp, we collect basic engagement data (sends, opens, and clicks) that can be attributed to your email address. This data is used to better understand our subscribers and provide aggregated insights.

If we make any substantial modifications to our Privacy Policy, email newsletter subscribers will be notified by email. The Baffler Foundation will promptly export or erase any email newsletter profile upon request.

### Social Media

The Baffler Foundation posts updates on various social networking platforms, primarily Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram. These updates are most often related to content published inside _The Baffler_ website, but may include promotional messages, such as offers to subscribe to the magazine or attend events. To enhance the visibility of these posts, we may use targeted advertising within social networks to promote our posts. This targeted advertising is generally based on anonymous demographic data such as location and interests. In certain cases, we may target advertising based on personal data, such as cookies stored from a visit to the _Baffler_ website.

The Baffler Foundation will promptly export or erase any personal information associated with our social media advertising upon request.

### The _Baffler_ Shop

The Baffler Foundation maintains a web shop that offers various products and subscriptions for purchase. This shop is hosted by Shopify. If you choose to make a purchase through our shop, we will collect certain personal information necessary to process your transaction and deliver your purchases, such as your physical address, email address, and phone number. If you have an existing profile as a magazine subscriber or newsletter subscriber, we will associate your shop purchases with your existing profile.

All payment information submitted through the _Baffler_ shop is managed exclusively by our credit card processor, Stripe. The Baffler Foundation does not retain or access any credit card data.

The Baffler Foundation will promptly export or erase any personal information associated with a shop purchase upon request.

### Additional Information

The Baffler Foundation’s Privacy Policy may change from time to time without notice to you. You should read this Privacy Policy each time you plan to submit personally identifiable information so that you understand how the information you are submitting will be used.

Any changes made to the Privacy Policy will be prospective, not retroactive.
